WE COMMEMORATE ALPAY GÖLTEKİN, WHO
CONTRIBUTED TO OUR ANCESTORS'...
...HEROIC EPICS WITH HIS MUSIC AND
SHAPED THE FLOW OF HISTORY, WITH RESPECT.
Please contact turkision@gmail.com
for any inquiries
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Father.
Father!
I’m going to kill you with my bare
hands, Osman!
Then I will feed the wolves and birds
with your flesh.
My uncle is not dead, Bahadır.
Father!
Bahadır is here, Father.
Bahadır is here.
My son.
Bahadır.
How di-
How did you find me?
Aygül.
Aygül, father!
She brought us here.
Oh my Aygül.
Oh my lioness daughter...
...oh my heroic daughter.
If my father was dead…
...I would have burned you alive at
the middle of the Kayı tent, Osman!
Bahadır!
Don’t forget that you will account for
what your mouth is capable of saying...
...in this world, not afterlife!
I don’t give accounts.
I only accept them, Osman!
Bahadır!
My son!
We successfully escorted Princess to the
place Osman wanted.
Thanks to Allah, we fulfilled this duty
properly, my Brother.
Now that we have found each other and we
are side by side...
...we will win many battles together,
brother.
Inshallah, brother.
What are we going to do now?
Are we going to Tent now?
What happened?
Do you miss the life style at Tent?
You can’t imagine, brother.
You can’t.
Brother, we will leave for Tent now.
You will go to Alişar’s mansion...
...and keep your eyes open.
You will inform us if something happens.
For now, Tent is no good to you.
As you wish my brother.
I waited my whole life so I can wait more.
Brother.
May you be careful.
We have lots of enemies.
For the ones who have brothers like
Konur Alp...
...even dragon-like enemies are nothing.
Don’t worry about me brother.
A soldier’s fate is never returning one
day.
Tomorrow it is, if not today.
May you give your blessing to me.
Alps! Let’s go!
You will die, Osman!
I will kill you!
Enough!
I need Osman alive.
Try not to cross your line, Böke.
He is the one who killed my brother.
His blood is halal only to us.
Hold you horses down, you crazy boy!
Or else I will kill you before Osman does.
Commander Böke!
This is our matter.
Osman is going to die!
Every matter corcens Geyhatu first…
…then me at this Border, Dündar Bey.
I see everyone is obsessed with me.
I am strong enough to fight all of
you.
So you can tell this to mighty Geyhatu
yourself, Osman.
I feel sorry for you.
He is more cruel than he is forgiving.
Unlike you, we neither walk around with a
leash on our neck...
…nor do we sell our soul to nobody.
Most importantly...
...we know no greater power than Allah.
How dare you try to stick your nose into a
matter of our Tent?
Osman killed my son!
Don’t you understand?
If you touch him...
...I will kill your only remaining son.
And, I will feed you with his corpse
until you puke.
Dündar Bey!
Commander Böke!
Enough already.
You see that Boran?
We are feasts for jackals around here.
They threaten each other over food.
Tie them now!
I will hold a feast every year on the
day you die, Osman!
Now that the biggest danger is tied…
…your absolute end is here, Osman.
It’s here.
Zöhre Hatun!
Don't do it, Zöhre Hatun!
I don’t want to hurt you.
If your Bey and children learn that you
got shot while running away...
...they will become sad.
Come with me and know your place.
In the future, I am going to make all of
you pay for days like today.
I will come with you...
…but don’t you forget about what I just
said.
As long as he lives, none of us...
…not even Geyhatu...
...can find peace.
What on earth do you have on your
mind?
Commander Böke?
I said his blood is halal to me!
Can’t you hear?
Enough!
Enough it is!
My Bey...
...these dogs have no intention of
killing us.
It’s obvious Geyhatu wants me alive.
You just stay ready, Boran.
We will get rid of Böke at the first
opportunity.
Then flee away.
Understood, my Bey.
Alişar Bey.
Tell me...
...what is happening, Alişar Bey?!
You told me you would hand me Osman...
...as well as you promised to avenge his
blood!
Yes, I did.
However...
...Geyhatu is the one who wants
Osman.
For what?
Why can’t you still understand that Osman
is not alone, Dündar Bey?
He wants to learn the one...
...who is supporting him.
Osman has been swimming in dirty waters
lately.
I will personally take him to Konya.
By the time Geyhatu is done with Osman…
…you will stare him in the eyes.
I promise.
Two of us will go to Konya together.
But...
...first, we need to get done with our
business at the Tent.
Do you understand?
Uncle!
I hope you don't bow your head and reach
that position...
...where you disregard our ancestors by
trusting that Alişar dog.
How can you still dare to talk?
Huh?
To take my revenge, I will find everyone
at the Tent who decided to join you...
...thus got their hands dirty with my
son's blood.
I will find and kill them all, Osman.
Kill!
All of them!
Dündar Bey.
Give me your soldiers.
I will take Osman and his Alp to Konya.
As you wish, Commander Böke.
You can’t know how happy I am right now...
...since you will not be attending our
wedding, Osman.
Be careful, Alişar!
You never know what's inside of a wedding
chest.
The biggest danger there is...
...no longer exists.
I’m leaving to get Zöhre Hatun.
Wait for the news from me.
My Bey, are we going to wait more to
take action?
If needed, yes my brother.
We will not compromise on our muslim
glory.
We will never bow our heads for personal
benefits....
...just like the letter 'Waw'.
Enough!
What are you keep talking about?
You can not understand what
we speak of, Böke!
We speak the language that turned
‘Kaysaria’ to 'Kayseri'.
...and 'Ikoni' to Konya'.
Stop mumbling, Osman.
These are all fairy tales now.
We will banish all of you like this.
What you call fairy tales today...
...are the very epics of tomorrows that
will haunt your people forever.
Mongol storm have already started to
blow your fire out.
We dominate every Turk there is
and continue our absolute reign.
We are going to see if you will be
talkative like this...
...once you meet mighty Geyhatu.
You are in such a hurry, Böke.
Every Turk tend to act like quenchless
sparkles of the hurricane.
You may say we are less in numbers…
…but even a single sparkling…
…will be strong enough to burn down the
world.
Come on!
No stopping till we get our horses!
You all swim in deep waters, Kılıç Alp.
You don’t care if you will drown or not.
Don’t you worry about us, Zöhre Hatun.
Osman Bey is tall enough and he can hold
his breath.
What about his hands?
Are they long enough to save you?
My Bey!
Dündar Bey.
Yes, Dündar Bey!
Dündar Bey...
...whose privates you captured…
...after you ambushed him while he was
carrying his daughter's wedding chest.
Dündar Bey...
...who you tortured.
Bow your head!
Just on time.
Just on time...
...you saved me from these
Shakirs, my Bey.
May my life be sacrificed for your path.
Osman?
Is he dead now?
Instead of me, Geyhatu is going to kill
him.
Don’t you worry about that.
Our era has begun.
Where is Bahadır?
I just told you.
Our era already has begun.
Today is a blessed day.
Bahadır is talking with Beys right now...
...to lit the fire of rebellion..
He will have everything ready.
Today, for Gündüz and his followers...
...the sun...
...will set for the last time.
Alişar Bey! Mother and father?
Please tell me they are alright.
No one gets away with
something.
Osman tired us with his madness...
...his stupidness...
...and his ambition.
He wounded us.
He killed us.
Now he is marching to his
own end.
And those who deserve to be
saved...
...are saved.
May your beautiful face smile.
Your father went to take Zöhre Hatun.
And Bahadır is on duty.
They will be here soon.
Thank Allah. Thank Allah.
Thank you Alişar Bey, thank you.
First, I shall reunite with my family.
Then, we'll take care of what is left.
We'll take revenge for my brother.
I don't know what could we do
without you, Alişar Bey.
May Allah Bless you.
My beautiful Aygül Hatun.
Now that you are here...
...my mansion is finally home.
I know many days that I returned to
this mansion with distress.
But never did the sun shined that
bright when I stepped inside.
Thank Allah.
Not at all.
If you'll allow me...
I have some matters to attend to.
Then we can sit and talk.
Alişar Bey.
Where is Osman Bey?
Is he still alive?
Osman is on his way to Konya.
He'll be interrogated by Geyhatu.
But...
...if a man gets interrogated...
...personally by Geyhatu...
...there won't be much left of him after.
Where is Osman Bey?
Speak!
If you speak, I'll make it quick.
Without pain.
Where is Osman Bey?
I saved your life again, Kongar!
Why haven't you kill this one?
He knows where Osman is but
doesn't speak.
Where is Osman? If you don't speak now,
I'll skin you alive!
Böke took him. They are going to Konya.
They are taking him to Geyhatu.
Let's move fast.
Balgay awaits.
How did you learn about the Monks of
Margareth?
Your uncle, Sungurtekin, was it him who
informed you?
Speak, Osman.
Or I'll make this trip way harder for you.
Where is Princess Adelfa?
Nobody gave you as much as trouble...
...as the children of Süleyman Ghazi...
...my grandfather.
This is just a beginning.
I won't tell you what I know.
You should think about yourself.
Speak, Osman. Speak!
Geyhatu would never let someone as
incapable as you, alive.
When we reach Konya, you'll be first
to be beheaded.
Enough!
You'll kill him.
I'll see you dead, Osman.
Take him.
May dark shamans mount wind horses
and come.
Today is for revenge.
Today is for bringing dark curses
to blue skies.
My valiant warrior, Kongar!
What happened in my absence?
What news have you brought me
about Osman?
Böke and Alişar captured Osman.
And now they are moving to Konya.
He is taking Osman to Geyhatu.
Geyhatu...
...who sold his soul to Budha in
Buddhist temples can't have Osman.
That ignoble who lost his dignity...
...that dog who tried to go over the
might of Tengri...
...can't take possession of Genghis' Laws.
He can't! He can't!
What happened in Konya?
Osman deceived Balgay.
Documents weren't real.
To make a feint, he must know
of the real one.
Otherwise, he wouldn't be able
to make a faint and deceive me.
I'll take Genghis Khan's Laws from
Osman's hands.
He'll pay for the disgrace he gave me.
What did Geyhatu do when he found
out that the documents were fake?
He decided on execution.
For all of us.
If we want to survive, only thing
we need to do is...
...taking the documents back from Osman.
Or Geyhatu will finish us off, sooner
or later.
We'll get Osman from Böke's hands.
We should go to Konya road fastly.
Don't underestimate Böke.
He is smart enough...
...not go on the main road.
The path our spies use,
he'll use that one.
Exactly.
They'll go that way.
We are leaving.
We'll get Osman before Geyhatu does.
Elders of Kayı...
...future of the Tent...
...my father sent his regards.
Thank Allah.
Is he healthy?
Yes, thank Allah.
But Osman tried to kill him, again.
But this time, we broke all
his plans.
We captured him and...
...sent him with Böke to Geyhatu
for execution.
Time for rebellion has come, then.
It has.
And it's now.
Wouldn't a night attack be wiser?
You take the lead if you desire.
And we'll follow you. Demirci Bey.
Not at all, my Bey. Whatever Dündar Bey
says is okay.
The alps following you, are they in the
forest?
Bamsı Bey doesn't let anyone move
in the Tents.
So, they have been waiting for our
word for a while.
Good.
Ready the horses.
We'll poke Bamsı Bey's eyes.
And we'll have Gündüz's head on a spike!
We have been dreaming of that day for
a while.
May Allah protect our Dündar Bey.
Amin.
His brother will leave the tents after
realizing the absence of Osman.
After all, a hunter is a prey...
...as much as he is a hunter.
What's wrong, Konur?
What's this hurry?
My Bey, we went to Osman Bey's place.
Kılıç Alp was dead.
-Kılıç.
What are you saying, son?
Gündüz, Gündüz...
It doesn't look good at all.
Snakes are on charge!
We shouldn't just stand.
Abdurrahman Ghazi, the Tent is
under your protection.
Don't worry, Gündüz.
As long as you are here, I don't.
Tell the soldiers to take battle position.
Tell women to get ready.
C'mon, c'mon.
Come on.
Don't be sad.
All these hustles is for you...
All the grief is behind us.
And until they speak--
From now, I won't let anything
upset you.
You should know.
I can't help it, Alişar Bey.
I can't feel good before seeing them.
Forgive me.
Mother!
Father!
Thank Allah, you are okay.
Thank Allah, that he didn't leave
us alone on this holy day.
We are fine, daughter. Osman
had fallen to his own trap.
As you see, we are here,
safe and sound.
-Don't worry.
-He hoped for my help.
But I didn't believe his fancy words.
He said that we are the same blood...
He tries to blind our eyes
with lies.
Just a little longer, daughter...
...every single one of them...
...will pay for what they have done.
-Any news from Bahadır?
-He is on duty.
All the preparations are done.
And now you are here, too.
Order will come to the Tent...
...and happiness will come to my mansion.
Tie them to a tree.
And whip them until--
Balgay...
Balgay!
Thank Allah.
Gündüz and Bamsı left. We know
who'll stick our from the people as well.
Everything will be easier
than we think, Demirci Bey.
Only Abdurrahman Gazi is left.
It's over once we deal with him.
Bismillah.
You're a lucky guy, Abdurrahman Gazi.
You won't be passing to the other side
without ablutions.
- Not so easy.
- Let's see.
Coem to your death!
Bring it on, Şahin Bey!
Allah!
I spent my life cutting traitors like you!
Come on!
Stop!
Stop, Abdurrahman Gazi.
Don't do the same mistake we did.
Get up!
Take them! Put them in the caged tent!
Gündüz Bey will judge them.
You promised to stay loyal to me and...
... you've destroyed your
promise twice, Osman.
Genghis Khan's laws were fake.
You humiliated me to Geyhatu
in front of all his soldiers in Konya!
That's better. You saw that
we're loyal to no one but Allah.
We'll stay here until...
... what you know comes out of your
mouth, and your spirit leaves your flesh.
I can't see how strong you are
while my hands are tied, Balgay.
Untie me so I can cool your
anger down in your blood!
You're a corpse for me now.
A corpse that lives until
I get the words from it's mouth!
My Bey! My Bey!
Because of your incompetence,
Geyhatu decided to execute you.
I'll kill you before him!
Forgive me! Almighty Balgay.
Forgive me...
... so I can serve you.
My Bey! What are we going to do?
Take Boran out of here.
Boran? How?
Listen to me, brother.
Do you agree to be my slave,
in exchange for your life?
I agree. I agree, Almighty Balgay.
I agree.
Then, you'll be on my side
with Nökers against Geyhatu.
Sharp teeth of a dog like you
mean the world to me.
It's my victory against Geyhatu.
Give Böke his weapons.
And hang Osman to that tree.
My Bey!
- Son!
- Yes, my Bey?
Check the Tent's entrance trenches.
We must not lack anything.
Fill the quivers.
We need those arrows ready.
- Right away, my Bey.
- Go!
What is it, Selcan Hatun?
Where are you going?
I'll visit our Sheikh, Abdurrahman Gazi.
I'd like to inform him of our situation
and get his blessings.
I'll send an Alp with you,
don't go out there all alone.
We're dependent on Allah...
... whether if we have an Alp with
us or not, Abdurrahman Gazi.
Thank you. You need those valiants.
Don't worry about me.
Thank you.
Send our best regards to our Sheikh.
He shall pray for us.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim
(in the name of God, the merciful and compassionate.)
May Allah allow us to complete
every duty with faith...
... to tame our desires...
... to see the days this lodge
will be enlightened by the light of Islam.
Amen, my Sheikh.
Now you tell me. You left
the Tent with the duty we gave you.
You were going to be our eyes
and ears there.
You were going to bring us the news
if something happened.
Why did you run out of patience
so you've returned, Bala?
My Sheikh, I thought...
... I will be more useful to you if
I stay by your side.
I'll have done something
better for myself.
You came here looking for
something better for yourself.
Why couldn't you find
such a thing in the Tent?
No, everyone in the Tent is alright.
I didn't hear a single bad
word from anyone.
Selcan mother, Gündüz Bey, and Bamsı
Bey all protect me, bless them.
What about Osman Bey?
What is he doing?
I don't know what Osman Bey
is doing, my Sheikh.
Only those who hear from him
know what he's doing.
But he is bad with his uncle.
Dündar Bey espoused his daughter
with Alişar Bey.
Their last argument was because of this.
Osman Bey...
... doesn't want Aygül to marry Alişar.
I don't know the rest.
Forgive me. I couldn't stay there.
I couldn't be away from you, father.
Okay then.
Let's say the child missed her father.
I personally never heard that
you left a duty incomplete...
... cried out when you
ran out of patience...
... or act impulsively.
Keep going.
Ambush! Its an ambush!
Come on!
Alps! What are you doing?
End of the road, Gündüz!
Dündar left the tent.
But his ears are still here.
What I'm trying to say is that
we need to watch our words near Bahadır
The bird of death landed on you.
While Osman is dying in Konya,
you'll die in my hands!
Gündüz! Leave Bahadır to me!
Leave Bahadır to me.
So, was everything a game, Bahadır?
Yes. But the games are over.
Attack!
We're here, Gündüz Bey!
What are you waiting for? Attack!
Bahadır! Bahadır!
Stop!
Stop, Bahadır!
Bamsı Bey! Your age is over!
Give up! Let's solve
this without spilling any blood.
Look, son. You're the grandson
of the great Süleyman Şah.
Don't make me take your life.
Get out of this pit that you're in!
Open your eyes!
Stop following your father!
Right, son?
You asked for it, Bamsı Bey!
Bahadır!
I'll tell you one last time.
Apologise, Bahadır!
Apologise! Stop this infidelity.
So that I don't kill you.
So I don't kill you.
Bamsı Bey! Don't you see?
Your age is over!
It's over! The Alps you've trusted are
fighting against you today, Bamsı Bey!
You don't understand!
You don't!
The age of those who tell the truth
never ends!
We'll always be alive!
Your weapons can't penetrate
our armour, you fool!
It can't! You'll drown in that
well of betrayal.
Every night, you'll wait for someone in
your own Tent to kill you, Bamsı Bey.
I pity you, Bamsı Bey. Surrender.
Switch to our side.
So that you can live the rest of
your days in comfort, Bamsı Bey.
Do you think we're after comfort,
you fool?
We're not afraid of death, thank Allah!
But your kind will live their lives
running away like dogs!
Your corpses will be buried in
the graveyard of traitors!
Geyhatu beat you up well.
Apparent from your anger.
Did those spirits and the bugs
you worship turn their backs to you?
I'm not in a hurry.
You'll eventually talk.
My Bey!
Those will stay on around
your neck until you talk!
My Bey! Hang on, my Bey!
Hang on!
Let him go!
I'm here, my Bey!
Hang on, my Bey!
Hang on!
Talk!
My Bey!
Let him go.
Talk.
You will tell me where
Genghis Khan's laws are!
You will tell me who
you got the laws from!
the secret power behind you is!
Now or never!
My Bey!
Let me go!
I wi-- I w--
I will talk...
My Bey!
I'll talk...
I will talk...
No negotiating, no trust.
You'll tell me everything you know.
That rope will stay on your neck
until I get Genghis Khan's laws!
If your Alp runs out of strength, you
won't have anywhere to step on.
I won't save you, know that.
Allahu Akbar! ( Allah is the greatest!)
Not only Genghis Khan's laws...
... I know everything about you
and your dogs.
You're trying to deceive me again, Osman.
But this time, I won't trust you.
You'll bring me the laws
I want to me, now!
Since you don't believe me,
let me convince you.
For example...
Kongar...
What about Kongar?
How you bought him from a slave market...
How you made him your slave...
For example...
... we can start from here.
Kongar!
How do you know this?
Who told you this?
If I'm lying,
why are you afraid that Kongar will hear?
How do you know this?
Emperor of Byzantium.
My only alliance is with him.
Come on! Come here.
Come on.
Burçin Hatun?
My daughter?
Aybars!
Burçin! My daughter!
Your fiance Aybars couldn't meet his
love in this world, but...
... he met his eternal love.
My daughter... Burçin...
Your meeting...
... will be on the doomsday.
Burçin...
My daughter...
Why?
At last.
You'll get what you deserve, Bamsı Bey!
We're here, Bamsı Bey!
Bamsı Bey!
Bamsı Bey! Are you okay?
- Are you okay?
Bamsı Bey! Who did this to you?
Was it Bahadır?
I'll strangle him myself!
Dümrul! Aras! What are you waiting for?
Go start a fire!
- We need to take these arrows out.
- No!
We can't do that now!
We'll take him to the Tent.
Konur! Go chase that traitor!
If you return without killing him, I will
kill you, know that! Go!
Konur!
My Bey?
My Bey.
Burçin...
My daughter...
My Aybars' fiance...
... did this to me, Konur.
- Gündüz...
- Bamsı Bey...
Burçin shot me...
Burçin...
My daughter shot me.
But! But...
Now...
If my Aybars...
... comes out of his grave...
Don't, Bamsı Bey.
I've made the judgement.
- Don't, Bamsı Bey.
- Gündüz...
I've made the judgement.
- Let's chase them!
- Don't, Bamsı Bey!
- Lets chase--
- Bamsı Bey, stop!
My daughter shot me.
Burçin shot me.
My daughter did.
My daughter shot me.
- Burçin Hatun! I owe you my life!
- Hurry up, Bahadır Bey!
- They'll catch up to us.
- Come with me. Don't go to the Tent.
They'll torture you there.
My home is where you are.
Let's go.
You made an agreement with
the Emperor to stop...
... the Monks of Margaret from
taking over the palace.
I was protecting my Tent.
And he was protecting his throne.
The secret powers behind me
were his spies.
They told me everything about you
and your dogs.
Prove it.
Then...
... bring me down.
Bring him down slowly.
My Bey!
What is an agreement I've made
with a slave trader years ago...
... doing in your hands?
What kind of capability is this?
I told you.
Both the Emperor and
his spies are with me.
I'm not alone.
Then tell me where
the Genghis' Laws that you're hiding are.
Geyhatu will come here.
To protect my Tent from his wrath...
... you will let me live.
I said no agreements! No, no, no!
If you don't kill me, I will give you
such an information about Geyhatu...
... that you'll take him down from
his throne and take his place.
That rope will stay on your neck...
... until I get the laws I want!
Agreed.
If I'm telling the truth, we'll both win.
Boran...
Bring the laws.
Cerkutay! Take the soldiers and
bring the laws to me.
Commander Balgay, if you allow me,
I want to take this dog.
If they try to trick us again,
I want to punish them.
Go.
Untie.
Now!
Walk!
Take this.
Göktuğ, what are we going to do, brother?
Osman Bey will do what's he going to do.
We need to get rid of those dogs.
Let's go!
Come on!
Now, tell me everything from beginning
to the end, Osman Bey.
You must be thankful to the Lord, Aygül.
This is a windfall for you.
A person needs to go through
hard times to be wise.
Alişar Bey supported us in our hard times.
He came up like an angel from my Lord.
He supported each one of us, you, me, and
your father.
I appriciate him, but I am worried about
what's going to happen when...
what happened in Kayı tribe is revealed,
Mother.
This has been happening since my father
became the Bey.
Look, Osman is on his way of Konya.
It seems like he will not return.
The killer of my son.
Hell be with him!
Right, but if something happens to Osman,
we all
When it spreads to the nearest tribes,
I am not sure whose side they will take.
Leave the nearest tribes aside,
Let it spread to the whole universe.
So that everyone can see the end of
those who...
stands against the tradition, rebels,
set their eyes to the throne.
Also, the bannerlord is on our side.
Aygül, be wise, my daughter.
If you be a good wife to him,
not only you...
but also your descendants will benefit
from this.
Also...
You are not worried about
Osman's situation, are you, Aygül?
If I were to worry about him, we wouldn't
be here preparing to the wedding, mother.
My only wish is to clear the Tribe from
Osman and his fellas and...
see my father on the throne which
he deserves.
You are right.
You are right, my emerald-eyed daughter.
We are in the right way, The ones who
are fake will vanish away, in sha Allah.
Thank lord, we made it to this day,
my Sheik.
After all those wars, we are building
our Khanqah (islamic lodge)
Our booty is this.
Booty, or entrustment, my Akça?
Does victory come from us, or Allah?
If they think as you think,
our situation is really bad.
Spill it.
- Summon the Yarens.
- Of course.
Yarens, my Sheik summons you.
In this mubarak Ramadan day,
you are working while fasting.
I wanted you to take a breath.
After emigration, Mecca polytheists
considered Muslims as a big threat.
Especially, they think Damascus is under
threat.
Because of that, they try to stop Muslims
before Muslims go stronger.
The name of the spy they found in Medina
is İbn-i Selule.
Don't forget, Yarens.
Time passes away.
But, there is always an İbn-i Selule.
At that time, Muslims learned that
Ebu Sufyan's caravan is....
on the way of Damascus.
Caravan, but what a caravan.
There were about fifty thousand
dinar(currency) worth items.
Ebu Sufyan realized that threat and
seek help from his friends from Mecca.
A thousand people go to
protect the caravan.
Our Efendi, who is the diamond of this
and the other world...
May Allah send prayers and peace upon him
He asks who to strike first...
Caravan, or the army of polytheists?
Most of them say caravan.
But when our Prophet starts to tell
the truth by the light of revelations...
... their thoughts change.
They understand that
Allah's desire isn't on that.
If they strike the caravan, they'll gain
an economical advantage and save the day.
But if they strike
the army of polytheists...
... their afterlives would be saved.
Our holy Prophet...
... wants the Muslims to save
humanity, not their day.
My Allah, in the surah Anfal, tells us
that even booty is temporary.
And says;
In the name of God, the merciful and compassionate
[Surah Al-Anfal 8:1]
The believers are only those who, when Allah
is mentioned, their hearts become fearful
... and when His verses are recited to them...
..it increases them in faith; and upon their Lord they rely
[Surah Al-Anfal 8:2]
The ones who establish prayer,..
...and from what We have provided them, they spend.
[Surah Al-Anfal 8:3]
Those are the believers, truly.
For them are degrees [of high position] with their Lord
...and forgiveness and noble provision.
[Surah Al-Anfal 8:4]
Long story short, friends...
A Muslim's goal should be
to help humanity, not get booty.
If not for the opportunities
Allah gave us...
... we wouldn't have started
this Lodge's construction.
So our success isn't from
our desires, it's from Allah.
Our Prophet and his companion
emigrated to Medina...
... to have the qualities
they believed in. But remember...
... Muslims emigration didn't end.
We'll continue emigrating to carry
the qualities to those who need them.
This Lodge's purpose will be this.
Hopefully.
With Allah's commandment and
our Prophet's sunnah...
... we're here to perform Aygül Hatun
and Alişar Bey's wedding.
Aygül Hatun, daughter of Dündar. Do you
accept marrying Alişar, son of Mahmut...
... with a dowry of
500 drams of gold?
- Yes
- Do You?
Alişar Bey, son of Mahmut. Do you accept
marrying Aygül Hatun, daughter of Dündar..
... with the 500 gold you've
promised to give?
- Yes.
- Do you?
- Witnesses. Do you bear witness?
- Yes.
By all the witnesses, I pronounce
you husband and wife...
May my Rab bless your wedding, and keep
you together until the end of time. Amen.
Father!
Alişar Bey!
What is going on?
What are you doing here?
- What are you doing, Bahadır?
- Everything is ruined!
They ambushed me and my Alps
in the forest! They killed all of them!
What are we waiting for, Alişar Bey? Let's
go and drown them in their own blood!
Now it's time to be a man!
- Father!
- Dündar!
- Dündar Bey!
- Father!
Dündar!
Father!
Take a look around with Böke. I have
somethings to talk to with Osman Bey.
Start from the Monks of Margaret.
Geyhatu was going to take
the Emperor down...
... and put Sofia in his place.
I've destroyed his attempt.
You gave the traitor's
names to the Emperor.
I took them from Böke's hands.
If you don't believe me, go ask him.
Huh? Go!
Monks of Margaret spies
are in the hands of the Emperor, right?
I did what you couldn't do!
Without one arrow, without
a drop of blood, I've defeated Geyhatu.
Is that why Geyhatu is coming?
I did what I could. I beat Geyhatu.
Now it's your turn.
You'll find and destroy him.
What about the information
you'll give me about Geyhatu?
Boran will bring the laws.
Then you'll release me.
Only then I will tell you.
If Boran doesn't come...
... I'll skin you alive.
You'll witness your flesh being
separated from your bones.
Pray to your religion, Osman.
So that your Alps comes here at once.
Tie him up.
Die, for the love of Erlil Khan!
Get him! Quick!
Melik! What does the doctor say?
He's excited, my Bey.
He'll be fine if he rests for a while.
Dündar Bey is old blood.
He'll be fine.
But there is no time to wait, Alişar Bey.
A bloody payoff is awaiting us.
If they want to spill blood, let's
finish the preparations, Bahadır.
I'll cut the veins of this region...
and they'll see how is it like
to play with us.
Come, daughter.
Bala.
Let me do it, daughter.
Helping my Sheikh is like a mission
for our Allah.
- Thank you, Selcan Hatun.
- Thank you, my Sheikh.
Welcome.
Come.
We were hoping to
get news from you.
Bala said that the tent's
conditions are troubled.
We didn't want to do anything without
Osman Bey's words.
Bala daughter.
Thank you. She stood by us. She
became a remedy to our grief.
She helped us.
But she couldn't resist...
some things in the tent, my Sheikh.
I know what Dündar Bey has done.
But I don't know what Osman
Bey is doing now.
My Osman...
he was played.
But he keeps fighting.
He sets a trap to a trap.
His intention is to show his uncle
what the truth is.
That's why...
he's objected Aygül's marriage.
His intention is to solve
this problem with Aygül.
Osman...
always thought about his tent and
left his own good behind.
He was sometimes mad, and
sometimes novice.
However, he always did the
right thing because...
his way was the right way.
That's why he'll always
be tied to Allah...
and he'll manage to get away...
the bad situations around him, Inshaallah.
Inshaallah, my Sheikh.
Inshaallah.
Thank you, my Sheikh. You
put my mind at rest.
I wanted to relieve and now I'm relieved.
- Keep praying for us.
- We're after the same purpose with not...
only our prayers but also
our hearts, Selcan Hatun.
We wish that the place that...
will set up in this region
to be holy for Islam.
Don't worry.
Kayı tent is more crowded...
than they think.
We have an unfinished business, Osman.
You're wrong, Böke.
You'll find yourself in the judgment day.
He can't go far away with an
arrow on his back.
Find him.
We were nourishing a serpent in our bosom.
Too bad.
My Bamsı Bey.
- Are you okay?
- Thanks, my Konur. I'm fine.
Thank you.
How could they dare? I still can't
believe it, Bamsı Bey.
I still can't believe it.
Even Burçin...
whom I see as my daughter...
disobeyed us.
This betrayal poisons everyone.
Kulucahisar's feudal landlord...
and the traitors among us.
They're all the same.
Unbelievers are our enemies. But
their hostility is clear.
But the tratiors aren't like that.
They seem like a friend and
they can hide hostility.
Şahin and Demirci are
waiting for their execution.
But the betrayal's pus keeps
suppurating, my Gündüz.
Then it's time to squeeze
the pus, Bamsı Bey.
Alps!
Today is the day to qualify our weapons.
Today is the day to
snub Alişar Bey.
We'll go and strangle him in his place.
Dündar Bey, you're doing wrong.
You should rest.
Dündar Bey, what are you doing?
My Bey...
Dündar Bey...
Why are you up? Why are you in a hurry?
You should rest.
We tell him but he doesn't
understand, Zöhre Hatun.
He keeps insisting to come.
Alişar Bey should
send news to the Beys around.
The tents should gather.
- Let's see what they'll do.
- There's no time, Hatun.
I should be with my Beys and horses.
No one can say that I've escaped.
There's no time.
Your wounds haven't got better yet.
Don't.
Even your shadow frightens people.
Let Alişar Bey prepare.
Then you'll hit the road. Then you'll take
our revenge.
Get my horse ready now.
Father, Zöhre Hatun is right.
You should wait.
I don't know anything about
laws and rights.
They killed my child for this case.
They can't kill my other child.
I'll take my revenge and take the post
that I have a right to...
and I'll kill the people who have...
objected me.
Brother.
This is a bullet dhikr.
He escaped.
They shot him
while he was escaping.
- Come on, Boran. Come on.
- Come on, brother.
Alişar Bey!
Open the door!
- It's time to talk.
- Gündüz Bey!
Let us. We'll break this door!
You know.
The door can't be locked
when the piker is inside.
- Come on, Bamsı Bey!
- Ya Allah!
Alişar!
Ya Allah!